Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
各位英语学习者，大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you part four of our romantic series called I'm Sorry I Love
今天我们要带来浪漫系列《对不起，我爱你》的第四部分。
You.
你。
Yeah, and today we've got some drama, don't we?
是啊，今天咱们可有好戏看了，对吧？
We got a lot of drama and we got a lot of useful language.
我们有很多戏剧性的情节，也有很多实用的语言。
Yeah, we're going to learn some phrases we can use to describe a mistake and we're also
是的，我们要学一些可以用来描述错误的短语，而且我们还会
going to learn how we can comfort someone.
我们将学习如何安慰别人。
We can make them feel better.
我们可以让他们感觉好一些。
Okay, exactly.
好的，没错。
So in our dialogue today, Veronica and her boyfriend are on a break.
所以在今天的对话中，维罗妮卡和她的男朋友正在分手冷静期。
Right.
对。
So what does it mean to be on a break?
那么“分手冷静期”是什么意思呢？
Well, it means you stop having a romantic relationship for a short time.
嗯，意思是你暂时停止一段浪漫关系。
So you can say we are on a break.
所以你可以说“我们正在分手冷静期”。
So we're not dating.
所以我们没有在约会。
We're not dating.
我们没有在约会。
But we don't date.
但我们也不约会。
Or we could say, let's take a break.
或者我们可以说，“我们暂时分开一下吧”。
Right.
对。
So we've got the state, on a break, and the action, take a break.
所以我们有状态“在休息”，以及动作“休息一下”。
Take a break.
休息一下。
Let's take a break.
我们休息一下吧。
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue and it's going to be a little bit fast and the
好的，我们来听一下对话，语速会有点快，而且
girl, I think she's crying.
那个女孩，我觉得她在哭。
It'll be a little bit difficult to understand.
可能会有点难懂。
But Marco and I will come back in a minute and we'll talk about some of the difficult
但马可和我一会儿会回来，讨论一些难懂的
language here.
语言点。
So I said, let's take a break.
所以我说，我们休息一下吧。
And since that night, I've been waiting for him to call, but I still haven't heard from
从那天晚上起，我一直在等他打电话，但至今没有他的消息。
him.
他。
You don't think he's seeing someone else, do you?
你不会觉得他在和别人约会吧？
Come on, don't be so dramatic.
拜托，别这么夸张。
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine.
我相信一切都会好起来的。
You think so?
你这么觉得吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
How could he do this to me?
他怎么能这样对我？
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
我肯定他在骗我。
Why else wouldn't he call?
不然他为什么不打电话？
But you two are on a break.
但你们俩在分手期间。
Theoretically, he can do whatever he likes.
理论上，他想做什么都可以。
He's the love of my life.
他是我一生的挚爱。
I really messed this up.
我真的搞砸了。
Come on, hon, pull yourself together.
好了，亲爱的，振作起来。
It's going to be all right.
一切都会好起来的。
But I still love him and it's all my fault.
但我仍然爱他，而且都是我的错。
I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being.
我简直不敢相信自己当时那么不成熟和自私。
I mean, he is a firefighter.
我是说，他是个消防员。
It's not like he can just leave someone in a burning building and meet me for dinner.
他总不能把别人丢在着火的大楼里，然后来和我吃晚饭吧。
I totally messed this up.
我完全搞砸了。
You know what, Veronica?
你知道吗，维罗妮卡？
I think you should make the first step.
我觉得你应该迈出第一步。
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
我相信他会原谅你的。
No, this is not going to happen.
不，这不可能。
I ruined everything.
我毁了一切。
Hey, do you hear something?
嘿，你听到什么声音了吗？
Guess what, it's your lovely firefighter.
猜怎么着，是你可爱的消防员。
Don't you know I sit around with my head hanging down and I wonder who...
难道你不知道我垂头丧气地坐着，想知道谁……
Wow, that's a romantic boyfriend singing in the street.
哇，真是个浪漫的男朋友在街上唱歌。
Yeah, yeah, that's amazing.
是啊，是啊，太棒了。
Have you ever done that for a girl?
你曾经为哪个女孩做过这种事吗？
No.
没有。
Well, have you ever sung to a girl at KTV?
那你在KTV给女孩唱过歌吗？
I've sung to a girl on KTV.
我在KTV给女孩唱过歌。
And karaoke.
还有卡拉OK。
Karaoke, yeah.
卡拉OK，是的。
So, but not so much as on the street with all the neighbors coming out to see me.
但不像在街上那样，所有邻居都出来看我。
Wow, okay, well, I don't blame you.
哇，好吧，我不怪你。
All right, let's take a look at the language that we saw in our dialogue on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们来看看对话中出现的语言点，在“语言点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言点。
All right, so let's take a look at our first word, seeing someone.
好的，我们来看第一个词，“和某人约会”。
Seeing someone.
和某人约会。
So, if I'm seeing someone...
所以，如果我在和某人约会……
You're dating them.
你在和他们交往。
I'm dating them.
我在和他们交往。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm frequently going out with that person.
我经常和那个人出去。
Right.
对。
So, but it's not very serious.
所以，但这并不严重。
No, it is serious.
不，这很严重。
But not really, it's more of a casual thing.
但其实也不是，更像是随意的关系。
It's not very exclusive.
并不是很排他。
So, if you are seeing someone, then you can also see another person.
所以，如果你在和某人约会，你也可以同时和别人约会。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Hmm.
嗯。
Well, I think sometimes seeing someone can mean actually they're your boyfriend or girlfriend.
嗯，我觉得有时候“和某人约会”可能意味着他们就是你的男朋友或女朋友。
Like I'm seeing John, he's my boyfriend.
比如我在和约翰约会，他是我男朋友。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, see, this is the difficult thing about seeing someone is that for some people it
是啊，你看，这就是约会的难处，因为对有些人来说，
means it's really serious, while for other people it means it's more casual.
这意味着很认真，而对另一些人来说，则意味着比较随意。
I guess it's important that you and your boyfriend or girlfriend share the same view on the meaning
我想重要的是，你和你的男朋友或女朋友对这个词的含义有相同的看法。
of this word.
这个词的含义。
Right, have to agree on what seeing someone means.
对，必须就“约会”的含义达成一致。
Okay, well, what's our next word, Marco?
好的，那么我们的下一个词是什么，马可？
Cheating on.
出轨。
Cheating on someone.
对某人不忠。
Cheating on me.
背叛我。
Cheating on someone.
对某人不忠。
Okay, so if you're cheating on someone.
好的，所以如果你对某人不忠。
Then you are like kissing or even having sex with someone who's not your boyfriend or
那你就是在亲吻甚至与不是你男朋友或
your husband or your girlfriend or your wife.
你丈夫或你女朋友或你妻子的人发生性关系。
Exactly.
没错。
So, if I say, she cheated on me.
所以，如果我说，她背叛了我。
That means that my girlfriend kissed or had sex with another guy.
那意味着我的女朋友亲吻了另一个男人或与他发生了性关系。
Right.
对。
But if I say, she cheated me.
但如果我说，她欺骗了我。
Yeah, that's different.
是的，那就不一样了。
That's different, right?
那不一样，对吧？
Like, maybe she sold you something for a really high price.
比如，她可能以很高的价格卖给你东西。
She cheated me.
她骗了我。
Yeah.
是的。
Or maybe she sold me something that was fake.
或者她卖给我的是假货。
Yeah, or broken or something.
对，或者是坏的之类的。
Yeah.
嗯。
So, cheated on is really different from cheated.
所以，“出轨”和“被骗”真的很不一样。
Okay, let's take a look at our next word.
好的，我们来看下一个词。
Messed this up.
搞砸了。
So, Marco, this is a phrasal verb and that means we can sort of switch it around a little
所以，Marco，这是一个短语动词，意思是我们可以稍微调整一下它的顺序，
bit, right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So, let's listen to some examples and then we can come back and talk some more.
那么，我们先听一些例子，然后再回来继续讨论。
Example one.
例子一。
I messed up on the exam and now I won't pass my class.
我考试考砸了，现在没法及格了。
Example two.
例子二。
When I'm cooking, I always mess up and burn the rice.
我做饭时总是搞砸，把饭烧糊了。
Okay, so messed up.
好了，messed up。
It's pretty clear, I think.
我觉得意思很清楚了。
Yeah.
是的。
All right, let's take a look at our next word.
好的，我们来看下一个词。
Immature.
不成熟。
So, when someone is immature...
所以，当一个人不成熟时……
They're acting really young.
他们表现得很幼稚。
Really young, right?
很幼稚，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
But it's not a very good thing to be immature.
但不成熟可不是什么好事。
No, it has a negative meaning.
对，它有负面含义。
Right.
没错。
It's normal for children to be immature.
孩子不成熟很正常。
Because they're children.
因为他们是孩子。
Right, but not an adult.
对，但成年人就不行。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So, we've got some examples that will help you to understand this word a little bit better.
我们有一些例子，能帮你更好地理解这个词。
Example one.
例子一。
Your toilet jokes are not funny.
你的厕所笑话一点都不好笑。
Stop being so immature.
别这么不成熟了。
Example two.
例子二。
Jeannie acts like she's 16.
Jeannie 表现得像16岁一样。
She's so immature.
她太不成熟了。
Example three.
例子三。
You and your friends always act so immature.
你和你的朋友们总是表现得很不成熟。
All right, so immature.
好吧，真不成熟。
Now let's take a look at our next word.
现在我们来看看下一个词。
Selfish.
自私。
So, a selfish person...
那么，一个自私的人……
Is a person who only thinks about themselves.
就是一个只考虑自己的人。
Okay, so I only think about me.
好的，所以只考虑我自己。
No one else.
不考虑别人。
Yeah, you don't care about other people's feelings.
对，你不在乎别人的感受。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's not a good thing to be immature or selfish.
所以，不成熟或自私都不是好事。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again.
好的，我想是时候再听一遍我们的对话了。
We're going to slow it down a little bit.
我们会放慢一点速度。
And this will help you to understand these phrases a little bit more clearly.
这能帮助你更清楚地理解这些短语。
So I said, let's take a break.
所以我说，我们休息一下吧。
And since that night, I've been waiting for him to call.
从那晚起，我一直在等他打电话。
But I still haven't heard from him.
但我还是没有他的消息。
You don't think he's seeing someone else, do you?
你不会觉得他在和别人约会吧？
Come on.
拜托。
Don't be so dramatic.
别那么夸张。
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine.
我相信一切都会好起来的。
You think so?
你这么觉得吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
How can he do this to me?
他怎么能这样对我？
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
我肯定他在骗我。
Why else wouldn't he call?
不然他为什么不打电话？
But you two are on a break, theoretically.
但理论上你们在分手冷静期。
He can do whatever he likes.
他想做什么都可以。
He's the love of my life.
他是我一生的挚爱。
I've really messed this up.
我真的搞砸了。
Come on, hun.
好了，亲爱的。
Pull yourself together.
振作起来。
It's going to be all right.
会没事的。
But I still love him.
但我还爱他。
And it's all my fault.
而且都是我的错。
I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being.
我简直不敢相信我那时那么不成熟和自私。
I mean, he is a firefighter.
我是说，他是一名消防员。
It's not like he can just leave someone in a burning building and meet me for dinner.
他又不可能把别人丢在着火的大楼里，然后来和我吃晚饭。
I've totally messed this up.
我完全搞砸了。
You know what, Veronica?
你知道吗，维罗妮卡？
I think you should make the first step.
我觉得你应该迈出第一步。
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
我相信他会原谅你的。
No.
不。
This is not going to happen.
这不可能了。
I've ruined everything.
我把一切都毁了。
Hey, do you hear something?
嘿，你听到什么声音了吗？
Guess what?
你猜怎么着？
It's your lovely firefighter.
是你可爱的消防员。
Okay, so we saw Veronica's friend trying to calm her down.
好了，我们看到维罗妮卡的朋友试图让她冷静下来。
Yeah, trying to comfort her.
是的，试图安慰她。
Okay, to make her feel better.
对，让她感觉好一点。
Let's take a look at some of the phrases she used in Fluency Builder.
我们来看看她在流利度构建器中用的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, so what was the first phrase that she said?
好的，她说的第一个短语是什么？
Everything is going to work out just fine.
一切都会好起来的。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
It's going to be okay.
意思是会没事的。
It's going to be okay, right?
会没事的，对吧？
Yeah, the problem will be solved.
是的，问题会解决的。
Okay, so if somebody is worried or somebody is crying, you can say, don't worry, everything
所以如果有人担心或哭泣，你可以说，别担心，一切
is going to work out just fine.
都会好起来的。
Okay, let's look at the next one.
好的，我们来看下一个。
Pull yourself together.
振作起来。
So what does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
It sounds kind of weird.
听起来有点奇怪。
I know, I guess it just means stop crying, relax, and take a deep breath.
我知道，我想它只是意味着别哭了，放松，深呼吸。
Just like calm down.
就像冷静下来。
Yeah.
是的。
Get organized with your ideas and your thoughts.
整理好你的思路和想法。
So you can think of maybe somebody who's got tears down their face and everything is sort
所以你可以想象一个人泪流满面，一切都很
of in a mess.
混乱。
If you pull it together, they clean up and they sort of relax, right?
如果你振作起来，他们就会收拾好，放松下来，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
Pull yourself together.
振作起来。
All right, and the last phrase that we saw, it's going to be all right.
好了，我们看到的最后一个短语是“一切都会好起来的”。
It's going to be all right.
一切都会好起来的。
So it's going to be all right means everything is going to be okay.
所以“一切都会好起来的”意思是所有事情都会没事。
Yeah, it's going to be fine.
是的，会没事的。
It's going to be fine.
会没事的。
The problem will go away.
问题会消失的。
You'll feel better.
你会感觉好起来的。
Maybe you could even say, it'll be all right.
甚至可以说，一切都会好起来的。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
It'll be all right.
一切都会好起来的。
Yeah.
嗯。
These are three really helpful phrases that you can use when you want to say something
这三个短语非常有用，当你想对遇到问题的朋友或同事说些安慰的话时可以用到。
nice to a friend or a colleague who has a problem.
没错。
Okay, exactly.
对，就是这样。
Very useful language.
非常实用的语言。
So let's listen to some more examples.
那我们来听更多例子吧。
Example one.
例子一。
Don't worry, everything is going to work out just fine.
别担心，一切都会好起来的。
I'm sure he still loves you.
我肯定他还爱你。
Example two.
例子二。
Everything is going to be all right.
一切都会好起来的。
We'll find your puppy.
我们会找到你的小狗的。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Okay, great examples and I think it's clear now.
好的，很好的例子，我想现在清楚了。
So let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and talk some more.
那么让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来继续讨论。
So I said, let's take a break.
所以我说，我们休息一下。
And since that night, I've been waiting for him to call, but I still haven't heard from
从那天晚上起，我一直在等他打电话，但至今没有他的消息。
him.
他。
You don't think he's seeing someone else, do you?
你不会觉得他在和别人约会吧？
Come on, don't be so dramatic.
拜托，别这么夸张。
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine.
我相信一切都会好起来的。
You think so?
你这么觉得吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
How could he do this to me?
他怎么能这样对我？
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
我肯定他在骗我。
Why else wouldn't he call?
不然他为什么不打电话？
But you two are on a break.
但你们俩在分手期间。
Theoretically, he can do whatever he likes.
理论上，他想做什么都可以。
He's the love of my life.
他是我一生的挚爱。
I really messed this up.
我真的搞砸了。
Come on, hon.
振作点，亲爱的。
Pull yourself together.
打起精神来。
It's going to be all right.
一切都会好起来的。
But I still love him and it's all my fault.
但我还爱他，而且都是我的错。
I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being.
我简直不敢相信自己当时那么不成熟和自私。
I mean, he is a firefighter.
我是说，他是个消防员。
It's not like he can just leave someone in a burning building and meet me for dinner.
他总不能把别人丢在着火的大楼里，然后跑来跟我吃晚饭吧。
I totally messed this up.
我完全搞砸了。
You know what, Veronica?
你知道吗，维罗妮卡？
I think you should make the first step.
我觉得你应该迈出第一步。
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
我相信他会原谅你的。
No, this is not going to happen.
不，这不可能了。
I ruined everything.
我毁了一切。
Hey, do you hear something?
嘿，你听到什么声音了吗？
Guess what, it's your lovely firefighter.
你猜怎么着，是你可爱的消防员。
Don't you know I sit around with my head hanging down and I wonder who...
你不知道我垂头丧气地坐着，想知道谁……
Okay, I really like this dialogue.
好吧，我真的很喜欢这段对话。
It's so romantic.
太浪漫了。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's romantic but at the same time romantic.
很浪漫，同时又很浪漫。
So we want to know what you think will happen next.
所以我们想知道你们觉得接下来会发生什么。
Yeah, will they get back together?
是啊，他们会复合吗？
Will they get married?
他们会结婚吗？
Will they have a baby?
他们会生小孩吗？
Maybe they'll break up forever.
也许他们会永远分手。
Maybe she'll move halfway across the world.
也许她会搬到地球的另一端。
Anything can happen so let us know what you think will happen.
什么都有可能发生，所以告诉我们你觉得会怎样。
Come to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave your comments on the lesson page.
来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在课程页面留下你的评论。
Exactly, and maybe you'll be right.
没错，也许你会猜对。
Yeah, you never know.
是啊，谁知道呢。
Okay, so we're out of time for today.
好了，今天的时间到了。
I hope you guys had fun and we'll see you next time.
希望你们玩得开心，我们下次再见。
Until then, it's goodbye.
在那之前，再见。
Bye.
拜。